Guide to the Henry Geldzahler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- December 1999 Acquisition, circa 1945-1996; 1; 39.04; (43 boxes)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    1) Approximately 10 pages original corrections regarding Japanese artist Shinro, Ohtaki; 3 page draft essay by Geldzahler on Shinro Ohtaki, original typescript with hand corrections and notations; 3 page final essay, clean copy, original type, uncorrected. 2) "Why We Feel the Need to Impose Order" - Essay for Architectural Digest - 2 page legal paper typed draft with hand corrections; 6 page final draft, original typescript with pencil corrections; 6 page xerox copy of final draft with hand corrections and notations; 1 page carbon copy of contract with Architecture Digest with 1 page letter; 2 additional letters from Architecture Digest. 3) Spare Parts: A Material for the Arts show - Approximately 15 page of correspondence, reviews, artist's lists, etc. for Department of Cultural Affairs, May 26, 1983 show. Also including, catalog introduction by Geldzahler, 1 page original with hand corrections.
  - Writings, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    1) An Aide-Memoire to Frank Lloyd and His Lawyers - 5 page original draft with hand corrections; xerox copy of same; 6 page xerox clean final copy of same - philosophical precis on how to give aid to the arts and artists. These were ideas presented to a judge at the request of Frank Lloyd regarding fulfilling his community service parole requirements following the Rothko trial. 2) 43 page folio bound "Application of the Carnegie Hall Society, Inc. to the Challenge Grant Program NEA, January 28, 1983;" 1 page original handwritten letter from Geldzahler to James Wolfensohn, regarding resigning from the board of Carnegie Hall; 1 page xerox typed version of letter.
  - Pop Art: 1955-1970 - curated by Geldzahler for the International Program of the Museum of Modern Art, toured Australian museums, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    1) 7 page proposal, xerox, by Geldzahler with hand corrections; 2) 46 page artists' biographies; 3) Approximately 40 page checklist for catalogue entries; 4) Pop Art, 1955-1970, The Classic Years; 2 page xerox typed essay; 5) Introduction Pop Art, 1955-1970 - xerox 27 pages hand corrected, 2 copies.
  - Pop Art: 1955-1970: approximately 27 pages Museum of Modern Art proposal drafts, original and xeroxed, heavily hand corrected by Geldzahler: Preface; "The Muse of the Marshall Plan"; "Pop Art: The Longer View" (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Pop Art: 1955-1970: approximately 150 page file miscellaneous correspondence including loan requests, bibliographies, checklists, gallery announcements, etc. (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Pop Art: 1955-1970: Catalogue from Miami University with letter; Pop Art 1955-70 catalogue; Biography and Bibliography catalogue for show (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Pop Art: 1955-1970: approximately 50 page correspondence: negative replies to loan requests (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Pop Art: approximately 35 pages affirmative replies to loan requests and loan agreement contracts (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Pop Art: 1955-1970: approximately 200 page various checklists (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Pop Art: 1955-70: approximately 30 page loan requests (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Pop Art: approximately 30 page internal (Museum of Modern Art) correspondence, regarding various aspects of exhibition (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Pop Art: approximately 80 page miscellaneous correspondence (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Pop Art: approximately 50 page hand written notes for proposal, and catalogue text: 22 page original on legal paper; xeroxed notes and pictures (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Pop Art: approximately 200 pages, mostly xerox drafts and checklists for Museum of Modern Art proposal. Includes numerous pages of handwritten notes, plus original typescript with author's emendations (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Pop Art: approximately 80 pages miscellaneous correspondence and lists (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Pop Art Exhibition Book: Australian Tour: 496 page comp. book including checklists, press releases, press clippings, lenders list, Geldzahler biography, reception invitations, etc. (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Influence of European Art on America, 1910-1930: lecture, Metropolitan Museum of Art. Approximately 80 page handwritten (ink) notes, 5x8 looseleaf paper in notebook, 1968 April 5 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Lecture on American Painting, 1900-1967: Metropolitan Museum, approximately 60 pages handwritten notes (ink) 5x8 looseleaf in notebook (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Brown "Maple Leaf" Notebook: Fogg Museum, Harvard - Approximately 80 pages handwritten (ink) notes, regarding various paintings - written in French and English, circa 1959 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Hardbound Notebook - 1958: 432 pages handwritten notes for classes, etc. regarding art (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Magazines and Catalogues with articles by Geldzahler, 1962-1977 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    1) The Hudson Review, Vol. XVIII, No. 1 Spring 1965. "The Art Audience and the Critic" by Geldzahler, page 105-109; 2) Extrait De La Gazette Des Beaux-Arts, November 1962. "Two Early Matisse Drawings" by Geldzahler, 10 page Booklet; 3) Twentieth-Century Art: U.S.A. from The Metropolitan Museum of Art - for exhibition in San Juan, Puerto Rico, text by Geldzahler (2 copies of catalogue); 4) Irving Penn - Photographs in Platinum Metals - Images 1947-1975, September 9-October 11, 1977. Introduction by Geldzahler; 5) The Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin (2 copies), April 1965. "Numbers in Time: Two American Paintings" by Geldzahler, page 295-298; 6) The Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin, November 1962. "Edward Hopper" by Geldzahler, page 113-117, (2 copies).
  - Magazines and Books, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    1) Art and Artists, April 1967. "Edward Hopper" by Geldzahler, page 20-23; 2) Newsweek - January 4, 1965, Geldzahler quote and picture, page 59; 3) Quadrum, No. 19. "George Segal" by Geldzahler, essay and interview, 11 page booklet; 4) Gazette Des Beaux Arts, November 1962. "Two Early Matisse Drawings", by Geldzahler, page 497-505; 5) Andy Warhol's Index (Book), rare publication with photograph of Geldzahler.
  - Books, Magazines, Catalogues, 1961-1974 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    1) Personal Preference: Paintings and sculptures from the Collection of Mr. and Mrs. S. Brooks Barron - Catalogue from the University Art Gallery, Oakland University, Rochester, Michigan exhibition, October 3-November 12, 1967. Introduction by Geldzahler, page 6. 2) Art New: September 1961 "Heller: New American-type Collector" by Geldzahler, page 28-32. 3) The Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin, April 1969. Introduction by Geldzahler with pencil corrections, page 365. 4) Hartung: Recent paintings by Geldzahler (in French and English) 16 pages. 5) Robert Rauschenberg: paintings, drawings and combines 1949-1964 - catalogue February-March 1964, Whitechapel Gallery: London - text by Geldzahler, page 4-11, text also by John Cage. 6) Homage to Andre Breton - 17 January-4 February 1967. Exhibition in Milan (Galleria Schwarz), 61 page catalogue - interview: Breton and Duchamp. 7) 21 Annee No. 119-120-121, September-December 1974. 136 page magazine "Recent Paintings" by Geldzahler, page 98. Cimaise: Present Day Art and Architecture Special Issue: Hartung. 8) Jean Arp - published by Metropolitan Museum, 1972, 46 page book with introduction by Geldzahler.
  - Books, Catalogues and Magazines, 1966-1981 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    1) The Centennial Celebration of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1870 and 1970, 32 pages. 2) Jean Dubuffet: Drawings, Introduction by Virginia Allen, The Museum of Modern Art, New York. 3) Real Life Magazine, No. 6, Summer 1981. 4) XXXXIII International Biennial Exhibition of Art, Venice, 1966, United States of America (for the Smithsonian Institute), Introduction by Geldzahler, page 19-23 (3 copies). 5) David Hockney: Kestner-Gesellschaft Hannover, 22, Mai-21, Juni 1970, Katalog 3/1970. 6) Grover Mouton: New Orleans at Zero Gravity - Booklet 1977 for April 16-May 15, 1977, New Orleans Museum of Art.
  - Books, Catalogues, 1959-1981 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    1) The Self-Portrait 1850-1950: Fogg Art Museum, May 5-May 30, 1959. A Museum Course Exhibition, 10 page booklet, text by Geldzahler, Henry G. Gardiner and Edward F. Fry. 2) Art in Embassies: Selected from the Woodward Foundation Collection for exhibition organized by the Washington Gallery of Modern Art, 24 page catalogue with introduction by Geldzahler 3) Upstart - 1981 arts journal of Barnard and Columbia Colleges, 56 pages. 4) American Painting - 1830-1970: American Embassy, Moscow - 40 page catalog with introduction by Geldzahler 5) Toward A New Abstraction - 1963 for exhibition at the Jewish Museum, 40 pages - "Ellsworth Kelly" by Geldzahler, page 16-17. 6) Panorama of Contemporary Latin American Artists - catalogue for New Jersey exhibition by the New Jersey State Council on the Arts, 62 pages.
  - Catalogues, Magazines, 1962-1989 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    1) David Hockney: Paintings, Prints and Drawings, 1960-1970. 2 April-3 May, 1970. The Whitechapel Art Gallery: London, 100 page catalogue (1 hard cover, 1 soft cover). 2) David Hockney: 5 page catalogue. Galerie Mikro, Berlin 1968. 3) Art News, January 1962 - "Parochial World-Views" by Geldzahler, page 44-45. 4) Francis Bacon: Recent Paintings, 1968-1974, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, March 20-June 29, 1975 - 82 page catalogue. Introduction by Geldzahler, page 5-13. 5) Jackson Pollock: Paintings and Drawings, 1934-1952. Exhibition 7 Sept.-24 Oct., 1989. Anthony d'Offay Gallery: London, 62 page catalogue with intro and chronology by Alan Bowness.
  - Pop Art - Australian exhibition: miscellaneous correspondence, news clippings, press releases, and radio transcriptions, regarding exhibitions. 9 page typed transcription of interview with Geldzahler, hand corrected by Edmund Capon (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    1) 21 page typed, hand corrected lecture, "Soho Lecture", May 1975 by Geldzahler for Artists' Space Fundraiser. 2) Typed letter (form letter) from Allen Ginsberg, May 18, 1982 at Naropa Institute, regarding Need for funds at Kerouac Conference - A.G.'s handwritten additions to Henry. 3) Letter to Allen Ginsberg from Fred WITH McDarrah, regarding Funding - forwarded to Geldzahler
  - The American Response to the School of Paris: 1910-1940. Lecture at Museum of Modern Art, 1968 April 5 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    1) 9 page original typed outline, "European Influence on American Painting," 1910-1930. 2) Various xeroxes lists, handwritten notes on seven 5x7 index cards (not in Geldzahler's hand), xeroxes from books on various artists.
  - Trip to California, May 1964. Article for Vogue on the L.A. art scene, 1964 May (Box 4, Folder 100)
    1) Rough draft original, typed, hand corrected, 10 pages. 2) Rough draft original, typed, proof read, hand, 8 pages. 3) Rough draft original, typed, hand corrected, 7 pages. 4) Xerox of Vogue, September 15, 1964, article "Los Angeles: The Second City of Art".
  - New York Art Galleries - New York Spy, June, 1967. An overview of the NY gallery scene: 15 page rough draft, original, typed, hand corrected; 16 page final version, xerox and original (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - The Curator and the Artist: American Association of Museums, Toronto, (lecture), 1967 June 2 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    1) Rough draft, 8 pages, original typescript, hand corrected by Geldzahler; 2) Rough draft, 9 pages, original typescript, hand corrected and pasted up by Geldzahler; 3) Various correspondence relating to lecture, booking expenses, etc.
  - The Influence of Criticism on Contemporary Art, for the College Art Association: 4 page rough draft, original typescript, hand corrected by Geldzahler; 5 page final version, xerox (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - New York International: for Harper's Bazaar, January 1966 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    1) 4 page rough draft, original typescript, hand corrected by Geldzahler; 2) 4 page draft, original typescript; 3) 5 page draft, original typescript, hand corrected by Geldzahler; 4) Various correspondence, regarding article.
  - Bennington Lecture: (Post-Victorian, pre-World War I art world, 1906-1913): 6 page draft, original, typed, hand corrected; 7 page draft, original, typed, hand corrected, 1962 May-June (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Research for D'Etente: Post World War I. 8 page handwritten notes on legal paper in pen (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Book Reviews (Box 4, Folder 107)
    1) Paul Klee by Felix Klee - 3 page original, typed, hand corrected draft; 3 page original typed, hand corrected draft; 2 page original typed, hand corrected draft. 2) The Story of the Armory Show by Milton Brown - 3 page original, typed, hand corrected draft; 4 page xerox, typed hand corrected draft. 3) A Letter to a Young Painter by Sir Herbert Read - 2 page original, typed, hand corrected draft; 1 page xerox, typed, hand corrected draft; 2 page xerox, final version. 4) Toward Reality by John Berger - 3 page original, typed, hand corrected draft; 4 page carbon copy, typed, hand corrected. 5) Late Modern: Edward Lucie-Smith and The New Painting: Udo Kufermann - 2 page carbon, typed, final version.
  - Interview with Robyn Denny: Video taped BBC; 2 page typed, hand corrected transcription; 1 page typed original questions - list; 1 page letter from BBC to Geldzahler, regarding Denny film, 1965 December 1 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Business in Support of the Arts: 4 drafts, original, xerox and carbon, hand corrected. 24 pages total. Final edit, 4 pages. Letter to Black Artists: Notes (handwritten) and drafts, xerox, typed, hand corrected. 20 pages total, final letter, 3 pages - On why no black artists were included in "NY Ptg and Sculpt. 1940-70" (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - List City Center Posters: 25th Anniversary of the City Center. (Vera and Albert List, arts patrons); 3 page original draft, typed, hand corrected; 3 page final version, carbon, typed, 1968 June (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art from El Greco to Pollock: Exhibition Catalogue: Notes, drafts and correspondence, original, typed-carbon, regarding John Marin - Marsden Hartley, slides and photographs of paintings. Two one-page entries on Demuth and Marin plus two additional drafts of same. 5 pages correspondence, 1968 May (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Milton Avery: 40 page xerox on Milton Avery. A fascinating unpublished study by Geldzahler, 1971 October 21 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Woodward Foundation Collection Exhibition: Catalogue Introduction for Washington Gallery of Modern Art: various lists and drafts for intro. 2 page Foreword in typescript with hand corrections by Geldzahler; 2 page typescript, final draft, 1967 August (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Art Education Today: Lecture at Grinnell College, Iowa; 2 color programs, 4 pages handwritten notes, 1968 April 11 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - James Rosenquist's F-111: for Museum of Modern Art Bulletin; 3 drafts, 3 pages each, typed, original and carbon, hand corrected; Museum of Modern Art Bulletin, March 1968 - Geldzahler article, page 277-281, 1968 March (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Two Essays: 1) Learning To Be An Artist, Harper's Magazine, December 1967. 3 drafts, 5 pages each, original and carbon, hand corrected. 2) An Examination of Art Education. 32 page draft, carbon, hand corrected and pasted, 1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - NYPS: Geldzahler Lecture: Lectures delivered by Geldzahler at the Met regarding NY Painting and Sculpture 1940-1970, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    1) 3 red-black "typewriter tablets" with handwritten notes (18 pages total); 2) 9 page legal paper handwritten notes for lecture, November 22-24, 1969; 3) Greenberg introduction, January 6, 1970 - 1 page handwritten; Motherwell intro, Jan 13, 1970 - original 1 page, typed with hand corrections; 4) Scull introduction, January 20, 1970 - 1 page original typed with hand corrections; 5) Hess introduction - 1 page handwritten for January 27, 1970.
  - Matisse Drawings, 1962 November (Box 4, Folder 118)
    1) 45 (approximately) page typed drafts with corrections, original. 2) "The Drawings, Matisse,": 21 page handwritten draft on legal paper in pen. 3) Photographs of Matisse drawings. 4) Extrait de la Gazette Des Beaux-Arts, November 1962 - "Two Early Matisse Drawings" by Geldzahler.
  - Hirshhorn Sculpture at the Guggenheim: approximately 30 page (9 pages x 2 drafts, typed, plus 8 pages, handwritten); checklist of exhibition (19 pages), 1962 October (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Happenings: 7 page article typed, original with hand corrections regarding Claus Oldenbburg and "Happenings" (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Contemporary Art Lecture - Museum of Modern Art - 32 page Mimeographed and Pasted up and hand corrected - transcription of a lecture by Geldzahler on modern art at the Met, circa 1966 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Interview with Helen Frankenthaler - 11 page typed original with hand corrections. Probably a transcription from memory. {Geldzahler stated this was how his early interviews were done before cassette recorders} (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - An Examination of Art Education (a lecture for Institute for Advanced Study in Art Appreciation, Ohio State University, July 25, 1966). 32 pages typed xerox hand corrected, 1966 July 25 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - New York Art Galleries - 16 page typed xerox, hand corrected. A fascinating overview of the New York gallery scene (Green, Castelli, Janis), the business of running a gallery, how galleries find artists and vice versa, the effect of "hype" etc., unpublished (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - California: 8 page xerox with hand corrections for Vogue (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Paragraph for McCalls: 1 page typed paragraph - original regarding current artist milieu; 1 page handwritten, in pen, draft, of same, 1965 December (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Talk on Burgoynge Diller: 1 page original, typed, with hand corrections (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Mark Rothko: approximately 30 page file containing artist biography, information, critical essays on; correspondence with curators regarding Rothko work; 1 transparency of work (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Offers of Loan, Gift or Purchase: 5 photos of paintings - Altman, Schoelropf, Thos Moran etc. (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Two Lectures, 1963 May (Box 4, Folder 130)
    1) "Brandeis Lecture" 5 pages typed with corrections in Geldzahler's hand, on the subject of the legacy of Abstract Expressionist painting; 2) "Recent Am. Ptg" essay for Cimaise, a version of the above. 5 page carbon with pencilled corrections in hand, by Geldzahler; 3) 24 pages of drafts with hand corrections of the above.
  - Museum of Modern Art Lecture - Recent Developments: 21 page hand corrected draft, xerox; checklist, 1963 February (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - American Paintings in the American Embassy: Moscow, February 1963 - 20 page final copy, essay and artist info. typed; various typed drafts, hand corrected; 1 booklet of the Russian publication (in Russian), 1963 February (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Museum of Modern Art Lecture - Origins and Early Development of Abstract Art: 21 page xerox of lecture, hand corrected by Geldzahler [Empty folder], 1963 January (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Pop Art: symposium at the Museum of Modern Art - Approximately 30 pages of typed drafts, xerox, hand corrected. Geldzahler's notes on this important symposium, defending Pop Art. Includes a letter from Peter Selz on the aim of the symposium, 1962 December (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Léger Article, Art News: 2 page typed, original, hand corrected "The Late Léger"; 14 page handwritten (pen and pencil) draft on legal paper; Art News, March 1962, Geldzahler article, page 32; Xerox of magazine article, 1962 March (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Radio Free Europe Interview: 10 page mimeographed transcription of interview with Geldzahler regarding Post WWII sculpture, 1962 May (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Werner Haftman, Art News: 3 page original, typed, hand corrected draft of Geldzahler's book review of Werner Haftman's Painting in the 20th Century; 19 page original, typed, hand corrected draft of same, 1962 January (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Hopper Article for Museum of Modern Art Bulletin: approximately 25 pages typed drafts, hand corrected, 1962 November (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Ben Heller Article, Art News: "The Ben Heller Collection" - 10 page typed, one original hand corrected draft; checklist of Heller's collection, 1961 September (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - NYU Symposium: "Untitled" - regarding art history - 4 page original, typed, hand corrected lecture; 1 page typed draft, 1960 November (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Edward Steichen and The First Decade, Art News: 21 pages handwritten - pen and pencil - draft; 4 page typed, original, hand corrected draft, 1961 May (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Outline For Scribner's: 3 page typed, hand corrected draft, regarding History of American Painting-Sculpture in 20th Century, 4 page carbon copy, final outline, typed (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - An Examination of Art Education, Ohio State University: 4 copies of a 32 page lecture with hand emendations by Geldzahler and his curatorial assistant, Kay Bearman, 1966 July 25 (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - First World Festival of Negro Art - Dakar: April 1-24th, 1966. 1) Telegram from Virginia Inness-Brown inviting Geldzahler to Dakar for reception. 2) 1 printed booklet regarding plans for exhibition. 3) Various lists and transcribed minutes from meetings in exhibition (Approximately 80 pages), 1966 April (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Interview with George Segal, November 1963, Art Forum, 8 pages handwritten (pen) notes; 4 pages typed, xerox, hand corrected final version, 1963 November (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Museum Talk: "William Carlos Williams, Charles Demuth and Jasper Johns." Approximately 70 pages drafts, typed, hand corrected, 1963 November (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Ellsworth Kelly: Interview for catalogue - Washington Gallery of Modern Art. December 11, 1963-January 26, 1964, circa 1963 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    1) Copy of catalogue; 2) Four typed, hand corrected drafts, 6 pages each; 3) Correspondence with Praeger Publishers regarding interview; 4) Isis International, March 1964 - Kelly interview appears on page 19; 5) 7 pages autograph notes--probably interview transcription by memory.
  - Jim Rosenquist, essay: original typescript, 7 pages; xerox of above; 5 page typescript with Geldzahler's corrections and rewrites by hand, 1973 June (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Milton Avery And The Sea: Foreword for catalogue, Thorne Memorial Art Gallery, Keene State College, N.H., September-October 1971. Original 4 page typescript, heavily edited and rewritten in Geldzahler's hand, cut and pasted; typescript of finished version of above; 1 copy of catalogue (Box 5, Folder 149)
  - Late Modern by Lucie-Smith and The New Paintings by Keltermann, 2 page typed original draft of book review, hand corrected (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Lectures: approximately 40 page file of typed correspondence, lists, handwritten notes, etc. regarding lectures given out of town - 17 page typed list of Henry's lectures, 1961-1974, listed by date. 8 pages handwritten notes on Abstract Expressionism (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - Weathespoon Annual Exhibition: 27 page catalogue from November 12-December 19, 1972, "Art on Paper" exhibition, juried by Geldzahler on pages 6-7; 1 newspaper clipping (with 2 photos) from Greensboro Record, 10/72 (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Milton Avery: 7 separate lists of Milton Avery paintings, with date, medium, size and collection (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Paintings of David Hockney: Four 33 page drafts, all heavily cut and pasted, with extensive revisions in Geldzahler's hand. This is the Introduction to the monograph Hockney by Hockney and shows the development of that essay (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Albright-Knox: 3 typed drafts, hand corrected, pasted, Approximately 25 pages each, "American Painting in the 1960's - The Albright-Knox Museum" (Box 5, Folder 155)